<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on CU Cybersecurity Club</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on CU Cybersecurity Club</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spring 2021 Schedule</title><link>/posts/schedule-spring-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/schedule-spring-2021/</guid><description>2020-01-25: Meeting 1 Location: Zoom
Time: 5:30pm Mountain
Subject: Wireless Attack Fundamentals Jacob talked about attacking wireless networks and how to gain access to a Wi-Fi network by de-authenticating devices and capturing their login.
Software used in the meeting:
airodump-ng aircrack-ng Commands and guide to folow what we did found HERE.
Slides
Meeting Recording
2021-02-01: Meeting 2 Location: Zoom
Time: 5:30pm Mountain
Subject: Password Cracking 2021-02-08: Meeting 3 Location: Zoom</description></item><item><title>Fall 2020 Schedule</title><link>/posts/schedule-fall-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/schedule-fall-2020/</guid><description>2020-08-31: Meeting 1 Location: Zoom
Time: 5:45pm Mountain
Subject: Intro to the Club What is the Cybersecurity Club? What do we do every week? What can you expect this semester, given how crazy the world is? Depending on attendee experience: Install and explain a Kali Linux VM OR HtB Slides Meeting Recording
2020-09-07: NO MEETING: Labor Day 2020-09-14: Meeting 2 Location: Zoom
Time: 5:30pm Mountain
Due to inexperience with Zoom&amp;rsquo;s breakout rooms, a recording for this meeting is not available.</description></item><item><title>Hack the Box: Admirer</title><link>/posts/htb-admirer-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/htb-admirer-walkthrough/</guid><description>Target IP: 10.10.10.187
Recon Scan Scan all ports, get version numbers.
# Nmap 7.80 scan initiated as: nmap -A -p- 10.10.10.187 Nmap scan report for 10.10.10.187 Host is up (0.065s latency). Not shown: 65532 closed ports PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 21/tcp open ftp vsftpd 3.0.3 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 7.4p1 Debian 10+deb9u7 (protocol 2.0) | ssh-hostkey: | 2048 4a:71:e9:21:63:69:9d:cb:dd:84:02:1a:23:97:e1:b9 (RSA) | 256 c5:95:b6:21:4d:46:a4:25:55:7a:87:3e:19:a8:e7:02 (ECDSA) |_ 256 d0:2d:dd:d0:5c:42:f8:7b:31:5a:be:57:c4:a9:a7:56 (ED25519) 80/tcp open http Apache httpd 2.</description></item><item><title>Hosting a Club Meeting</title><link>/posts/hosting-a-meeting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hosting-a-meeting/</guid><description>Things you should probably do at the start Plug the Slack: https://cucybersecurityclub.slack.com Plug the site: https://cucybersecurityclub.com/ Mention competition teams if recruiting Welcome new members Brief overview of the meeting agenda or introduction of guest speaker Things you should probably do at the end Thank guest speaker (if appropriate) Thank everyone for coming Give a blurb about next week&amp;rsquo;s meeting topic or speaker Plug the Slack</description></item><item><title>Lesson: Basic Networking</title><link>/posts/lesson_networking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lesson_networking/</guid><description>This is a rough lesson plan/script for a meeting of the club. It covers some very basic networking concepts using netcat and ssh. This is intended to be used by a presenter, but if you missed the meeting it should be quite readable.
Slide Deck
Motivation Networking is fundamental to almost all computer systems, and therefore it is also fundamental to offensive and defensive security. A basic understanding of networking opens up the world of security methods and tools because most of them rely on networking and cannot be understood without a baseline.</description></item><item><title>Linux Security Modules</title><link>/posts/linux-security-modules/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/linux-security-modules/</guid><description>Disclaimer: I threw these notes together for CU Boulder&amp;rsquo;s Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition team for spring 2020. There may be some inaccuracies, and parts of the notes are still incomplete.
Introduction The Linux kernel has a built-in discretionary access control (DAC) system for controlling system resources. DACs are characterized by the fact that the owner of a resource may grant somebody else access to that resource; for instance, in Linux, the owner of a file could run chmod +rwx myfile to give every user on the system read, write, and execute permissions to the file.</description></item></channel></rss>